Guide to the Arthur Bernard Recknagel papers, 1948-1961.
Recknagel, Arthur Bernard papers, 1948-1961.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Arthur Bernard Recknagel papers, 1948-1961.
1891
Arthur Bernard Recknagel, 1883-1962.
.4 cubic ft.
Monthly reports, minutes, printed material, and a transcript of an interview.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Monthly reports, minutes, printed material, and a transcript of an interview with Recknagel concerning his career in forestry education and management.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Recknagel served as a U.S. Forest Assistant, 1906-07; Chief of Reconnaissance on National Forests of the West, 1907-08; Chief of Silviculture, Southwestern District, 1908-10; Assistant District Forester, 1910-13; Professor of forestry at Cornell University, and also chairman of the department; Technical Director of Forestry, St. Regis Paper Company; author.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Monthly reports, minutes, printed material, and a transcript of an interview with Recknagel concerning his career in forestry education and management.
Included are Recknagel's monthly reports for the St. Regis Paper Company and related materials on the management of St. Regis lands, research, conservation, government policies, and other matters of interest to the forest products industry; snapshots of the St. Regis River area and forest operations in New Hampshire; pamphlets, reports, minutes, programs, clippings, and other mimeographed and printed materials concerning forestry management in general and meetings of various forestry and conservation associations, including the Forestry Committee of the American Paper and Pulp Association, the Forest Industries Council, the Society of American Foresters, the Fourth American Forest Congress, and the Western Forestry and Conservation Association; and a transcript of an interview (1958) in which Recknagel discusses his work with the U.S. Forest Service, his career at Cornell, and related subjects.
Detailed item list available in accession folder.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Recknagel, Arthur Bernard, 1883-1962.; American Paper and Pulp Association.Forestry Committee.; Cornell University. College of Forestry.; Forest Industries Council.; Society of American Foresters.; St. Regis Paper Company.; United States. Forest Service.; Western Forest and Conservation Association.; American Forest Congress.
Subjects:
Conservation of natural resources.; Forest conservation--United States.; Forestry law and legislation.; Forestry schools and education.; Forests and forestry--Economic aspects.; Forests and forestry--New Hampshire.; Forests and forestry--New York (State); Paper industry--New York (State); College teachers.; Foresters.
Places:
St. Regis River (N.Y.)--Description--Views.
Form and Genre Terms:
Oral histories.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Related collection: Empire State Forest Products Association. Records, #1280.
Related collection: Northeastern Wood Utilization Council. Records, #1964.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- St. Regis Paper Company Forestry Department, monthly reports, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- St. Regis Paper Company Forestry Department, monthly reports, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- St. Regis Paper Company Forestry Department, monthly reports, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- St. Regis Paper Company Forestry Department, monthly reports, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Oral history interview, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Photographs of Adirondack Logging", 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "History of Lyons Falls" by Clarence L. Fisher, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)